[grunts]
Geez, he's better than last time.
Not to mention he's beefed up, too.
And yet, he still seems
to be faster than before.
[student 1] Even our second-years
don't stand a chance against him.
[both] Thank you for the match.
You're really tearing it up
out there, Yusa.
But this match just now,
you could've stopped
five more of his points.
In the second half, you used a cut,
but let me tell you,
if it were me, I would've
smashed it right back at him.
- [snoring]
- No naps!
I don't have any free time
to talk to you right now, Yakushiji.
If you have time to sleep,
you have time to talk.
Can't you see? I'm clearly taking a break.
I wanna be ready
to go up against that guy,
so I need to make sure I'm in good shape.
[Yakushiji] Oh, Haryu?
Well, everybody knows he's
Eimei's best badminton player.
And not that we like to bring it up,
but he made it to nationals.
He always manages to aim
for the toughest spots on the court,
so it's pretty fun.
Huh? That ain't fun, kid!
Really?
Yusa! Sorry it's back-to-back,
but you're up.
Against who?
They said it's Inomata.
He's a first-year like you.
Inomata?
Ready to play.
[Yusa] Oh.
It's the guy who told me
where the gym was earlier.
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 18
I KNOW
[upbeat instrumental music playing]
[Taiki] Let's go!
Huh.
Let's have a good match!
Yeah, good luck.
Hey! It's Inomata's turn!
Looks like the match is about to start.
Girl, what are you doing?
Didn't you promise him
you'd be there to cheer him on?
Yeah, I said that I would come watch.
I didn't promise any cheering.
It's the same thing.
Isn't this a revenge match against the guy
he lost to at prefectural qualifiers?
Yeah, it is.
Look, I know that, but...
I don't wanna see him how he was that day.
I didn't have any idea
of what I could
possibly say to him then, either.
Why are you assuming
he's gonna lose this time, though?
[exclaims] That is not
what I'm trying to say!
- Oh, it started!
- [Hina gasps softly]
Look, Hina, I don't think you need to
worry about what you're gonna say to him.
I do think you should get up and watch
the match with me for your own sake.
Oh. He's rallying well.
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
[gasps]
[Nagisa] Everybody's playing pretty well.
[Chinatsu] They're supposed to be
the best school in our prefecture.
Oh. He just scored!
Wait, which court are you looking at?
It's second from the left in the back.
All right, let's see.
[grunts] Yes!
Uh... Chii, so if I've got this wrong,
I apologize...
[Chinatsu] Hm?
Then again, maybe I shouldn't...
Spit it out.
By any chance,
when I called you on your birthday,
were you together with that guy?
[Chinatsu exclaims]
Before I hung up,
I heard another voice for a second.
So does that mean
the two of you are dating?
Just tell me, come on! I am your friend!
You may be in the same gym,
but you don't have
to get all shy about it!
[Chinatsu sighs]
It's not like that.
You know how a family's
been letting me live with them?
That family's Taiki's.
Huh?
Both of our moms know each other.
And they happened to have
a spare room open, so I--
GRAB
- Huh?
- Are you a freakin' idiot?
I am super pumped
that you decided to stay in Japan.
But living with a boy
when we're all dating-age?
You just don't do it!
Tell me, what if something happens?
Don't you know that saying,
"all men are beasts"?
Like, you know what
my little brother does?
His... [elephant roars]
goes... [cartoonish gunshot] in the house!
You said "if something happens."
It won't.
[Nagisa] That pause implies it did.
[sighs] Look,
I acknowledge that I don't know
every last detail of the situation.
But at least I wish you would've
told me about it sooner.
For that, I'm sorry.
- [grunts]
- No way!
The match just started,
but the other guy's dominating.
[sighs] Still... I don't get...
how you could even consider
living with a stranger like that.
Thing is, it's not like
Taiki was a total stranger.
[both grunting]
[Nishida] Ah, so close!
He's keeping the rally going,
but can't actually
take the point in the end.
It's totally meaningless
unless you can score.
Haryu, come on.
You could stand to be
a little nicer to Taiki.
- Hey, we've seen you lose to him once!
- Come on!
[Haryu] This may be a practice match,
but if you don't step it up a notch,
you're gonna get left behind again, Taiki.
[dramatic music playing]
[panting]
[Taiki] I just casually decided
I wanted to go to nationals.
And now I wanna punch myself for it.
I have to be as good,
or even better than him.
When I beat Haryu, I thought that meant
nationals were right around the corner.
But in reality,
everybody else went to compete,
and I watched from the sidelines.
Then on top of that...
I was flattered.
Surprised, but flattered.
Still, somewhere in my heart...
I thought, "Me?"
[exhales]
Hey, is he all right?
Your housemate, I mean.
His movements seem frantic.
Doesn't he look desperate?
[grunts]
I'm sure that he's fine.
He's just gotta move his legs.
[Taiki] And then there was that time...
From Chinatsu.
They lost their game.
[Taiki] When Chinatsu was feeling low...
[grunts]
You idiot! Not there!
What the hell are you doing? Come on!
This is where Yusa shines.
He's running Taiki all over the court.
[Taiki] I was happy
I'm the one Chinatsu turned to.
I wanted to cheer her up.
But...
Who do I think I am?
[grunts nervously]
[grunts]
[gasps]
- You good?
- Yeah.
[Yusa sighs]
[game resumes]
[both grunting]
[pants]
Badminton is a tough sport, huh?
Keeping up with a birdie that moves
that fast has got to tire you out. Crazy.
[grunts]
[Hina] The Taiki I know...
has fun despite all the challenges.
[grunts]
[Hina] But this Taiki...
I've never seen this Taiki before.
[Taiki grunting]
Argh, it's out! And all for nothing.
That was his chance right there.
At the end of a long rally,
missing can really screw with your head.
And he was already worn out
after the first game.
[panting]
[exhales]
[Chinatsu] I'm starting to understand
what Taiki meant when he said...
[Taiki] It's just me out on the court,
and I'm in control of the match's outcome.
I know, Taiki.
I know how hard you've worked
at morning practice every day.
At first, I noticed there was some boy
who was always there.
But it was literally every day.
If he was there before me,
I'd make it a competition
and come earlier the next day.
You once said to me...
[Taiki] You were here practicing
the day after you graduated
from your junior high club.
[Chinatsu] But I saw you, too.
I saw you practicing the very next day
after your final match of junior high.
[grunts]
- Keep it up!
- You're doing good! Yeah!
Nothing's getting past you!
[both grunting]
[inspirational music playing]
[both panting]
[Yusa] It's uncanny.
He's getting faster and faster.
[game resumes]
[Chinatsu] Even on rainy days,
on windy days.
[grunts]
- You got this, Taiki!
- Pedal to the metal!
[both grunting]
[all gasp]
[Chinatsu] No matter what the day brought,
you never stopped moving forward.
I know that.
[grunts]
[Yusa huffs]
[pants]
[Sajikawa player] Of course the final game
is a real nail-biter.
It's like Yusa awakened
a sleeping beast from its slumber.
This guy wasn't even on our radar before.
We've got a new rival standing in our way
of next year's nationals, and yet...
it seems like he's having fun.
[both grunting]
This rally is seriously intense, dude.
Our man, Taiki,
he's returning every single shot...
No, wait. He's actually starting to...
Taiki just won the match!
[all cheering]
[boy 1] Nice work!
[boy 2] You killed it!
[panting]
Incredible! Taiki did it! He won!
'Kay. Back to rehearsal we go.
What?
You're okay with leaving
and not saying anything to him?
Wait, what... Hina?
Nice one, Taiki!
To be honest, I didn't think
that you were gonna win, dude.
But wow, what a match!
To be honest, I didn't think
you were gonna win, dude.
But your game's really come along.
- Taiki. Your opponent.
- [Taiki] Right!
Thank you for the match.
[Yusa] Hey.
[Taiki gasps softly]
I'm still...
not satisfied yet.
One more match then?
Are you an idiot?
You're obviously dead on your feet.
Yusa, you too.
'Cause later,
you're gonna have to take me on.
[laughs]
I can't move anymore.
[inhales, exhales deeply]
I guess I am getting better.
[peaceful music playing]
I just won!
[grunts]
[Chinatsu] You'll get sick
if you fall asleep there.
[Taiki] Hm?
Oh, Chinatsu!
That's right, she told me she'd come.
Left or right, you pick one.
Huh?
My treat. Choose left or right.
- The right one.
- Right.
[Taiki] Thank you very much.
I was actually really thirsty.
What was the left one, by the way?
I'm holding it.
So they were both the same!
There's that childlike side of her.
- No, they weren't.
- [exclaims]
'Cause the right one
was the one charged up
with my "high five" energy.
[Taiki] No wonder
I don't feel tired anymore.
Why is Pocari sweet
when you aren't exercising,
but when you are exercising,
it doesn't taste as sweet?
It's 'cause you're exhausted.
Sure, I guess that's true, but...
Also, you kinda sweated a lot.
So you need to rehydrate.
[sniffs] I must've looked dumb back there.
No, you didn't look dumb.
You looked pretty cool.
That's nice of you.
But today...
my winning is really all thanks to you.
[gasps]
[Taiki] You're at morning practice
every day,
and then run miles and miles
at team practice.
I think there are a lot of things
I've been able to do,
just because
I've watched you work so hard.
So I will just
keep following your example.
Today's match was still pretty close,
but I'll score more next time.
[grunts]
[singing "Nagisa" by Spitz
from the distance]
Oh, I know this song.
They must be practicing
for the school festival.
That's right.
It's just around the corner, huh?
[Taiki] Wow, yeah, it almost fall.
It's so much cooler now
than it was in August.
[singing continues]
[singing "Nagisa" by Spitz]
[In English] I thought, for some reason,
you'd be good at singing.
- [exclaims] Hey!
- [laughs]
Did you need to say that out loud?
Okay. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I said it 'cause I was happy
to see a new side of her.
Are you good at singing, Taiki?
Nah, just average.
Why do I not believe you at all?
No, really.
Hina's actually a pretty good singer.
She gives off that vibe.
And speaking of...
Hina came to watch your match, too.
Oh, right.
She had a break from rehearsing the...
[Hina] Wanna do it for real?
...play.
Ah, whatever,
you could say I won
'cause of everyone's support, right?
I gotta chill out.
It's not like the two of us
actually did it.
- Is the play going well?
- [gasps]
I saw folks making set pieces
in the courtyard.
Yeah, so far.
It's moving along for the most part.
Yeah? That's great!
I'll be there.
Sounds good!
The adaptation is unique,
so it should be fun.
- And the kiss?
- It definitely didn't happen!
Huh?
[groans]
I was just wondering
how your class will handle it in the play.
Uh, they are... they're just gonna fake it.
[Nishida] Huh? Taiki! Where are you?
- Well that's my cue. Bye!
- Bye.
[Coach Yuasa]
Thank you for everything today.
[Sajikawa coach] Same to you.
- [boy 1] We're heading out.
- [boy 2] This way, c'mon.
- [Taiki] Yusa.
- Hm?
You left this.
It's yours, isn't it?
Oh. Thank you.
Sure.
[boy] Inomata!
- See ya.
- Inomata.
What's up?
Your name...
Is it the kanji for "wild boar"
and "hip joint?"
Well, you're not wrong.
I can't remember anyone's names
unless I learn what characters
they write them with.
So, later,
Inomata.
Yeah, later.
It'll be a real match next time.
Hey, Haryu, wanna switch--
- Better to leave him.
- Huh?
Wait, why, though?
[Nishida] Because he just lost to Yusa.
I don't recommend poking that bear.
[Yukiko] Taiki! Dinner is ready!
Taiki!
[Dad] He must be asleep.
His food will get cold, though.
Aw, let the kid catch some Z's honey.
Didn't he have a practice match today?
- [snoring]
- [Dad] He looked pretty worn out.
[announcer]
It's the final match of the qualifiers!
And what a heated match it is!
An intense rally continues...
- And Inomata scores the final point!
- [yells]
[announcer] Taiki Inomata from
Eimei Private High School is the champion!
I lost, Inomata.
You destroyed me.
Rematch?
- How 'bout right now?
- Huh?
[Chinatsu] Taiki.
[grunts]
Hi, Chinatsu.
You were watching me?
Mm-hm. Congratulations, champion.
You looked great out there.
Thank you very much.
And now, a congratulation smooch.
What?
Wait...
Oh, no.
Chinatsu.
TUG
Oh, no, not on my watch.
Hina?
Uh...
[screams]
What kind of dream was that!
[closing theme song playing]